Tammy Jones

Accounting & Administrative Professional

Auburn, AL 36832 tammyjonescrabb4_9ty@indeedemail.com 6786098505

A detail oriented and efficient analyst with over 13 years of experience in account analysis. As a recipient of multiple customer commendations for exceptional service and organizational skills, I meet and exceed key performance indicators remaining above center averages in addition to increasing peer performance by 20% in the first month of productivity.

#readytowork

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Master's of Accounting Student

Keller Graduate School of Management Online January 2019 to August 2020

Certified public accounting exam readiness courses offered via Becker CPA Review, advanced research for accountants, advanced auditing, leadership, corporate accounting and management

QUALITY ANALYST/SERVICE DELIVERY SPECIALIST

HR PAYROLL & BENEFIT ADMINISTRATION, CHIME SOLUTIONS INC - Morrow, GA August 2017 to May 2018

MORROW, GA

(MAJOR CLIENTS: US BANK, Marriott, AMERICAN AIRLINES AND PEPSICO) AUG 2017- MAY 2018

- Served as interim team manager and quality coach, composing reports including QA scores, recommendations and action plans for coaching
- Analyzed calls to determine the root cause of missing pay, hours, data or benefits
- Corrected events by re-running the benefit elections to allow specific packages enrollment during the annual enrollment period or the silent correction window
- Reviewed performance standards to ensure associates met or exceeded both company and client goals
- Reported weekly feedback to management on performance, time management, KPI and adherence to schedule
- Conducted quality evaluations of analysts, including call listenings, case browses and interactive sessions/side-by-sides
- Evaluated analyst/customer interactions utilizing reporting analytics
- Collaborated with team leaders/supervisors and department leaders to discuss analyst progress and to report team patterns and trends in preparation for client meetings

- Identified and reported weekly QA concerns to management performing root cause analysis to propose and implement recommendations to improve processes
- Achieved subject matter expert status in the administration and proper implementation of specific client data on COBRA, benefit eligibility, package availability, regional availability, management of eligibility data, responding to HR, billing and payroll inquiries and addressing carrier file errors
- · Updates to client data in the correction of payroll discrepancies and other clerical duties

TECHNICAL SUPPORT ANALYST

CAREER CONNECTIONS INC - Atlanta, GA April 2013 to August 2013

Served as an outsource agent providing technical support for Apple iOS devices (iPod, iPad and iPhone)

- \circ Assessed each caller's scenario to identify the source of underlying problems and oversee its resolution, documenting each step of the process
- Promptly responded to complex technical questions via phone or email
- Researched customer concerns and created tickets to resolve high priority inquiries
- · Collaborated with alternate departments to resolve billing issues and customer complaints
- Educated customers on how to manage their accounts including accessing secure account information and updating payment methods
- Troubleshooted devices educating customers on the upkeep of their devices and upselling Apple Care warranty packages to eligible customers
- Processed payments with the highest level of confidentiality

REDIRECT OPERATOR/PRE-SALES CONSULTANT/.COM BILLING AND SERVICE ANALYST

AFNI INC - Opelika, AL February 2006 to June 2011

Participated in outsource customer engagement assisting with billing, ordering, service and directing calls

- Facilitated inbound call inquiries while providing timely analysis and customer support related to billing, order status, order placement, cancellation, delivery and page load errors
- Submitted maintenance requests to remedy technical issues encountered during the vzw.com order process
- Demonstrated integrity while securely requesting order information for billing and customer contact information to allow for safe and secure processing
- · Initiated intradepartmental communication to resolve billing issues and other clerical duties
- Created credit memos for erroneous or changed billing information to explain prorated charges and set expectations for the upcoming billing period
- Increased sales margins by proactively selling other company products and services
- Obtained subject matter expert status to provide expected value, integrity and prompt service
- · Assisted with information gathering, supervisory call answering and training new hires as needed

Education

Master's in Accounting

KELLER'S GRADUATE SCHOOL OF MANAGEMENT OF DEVRY UNIVERSITY

Bachelor's in BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION/ACCOUNTING

STRAYER UNIVERSITY - Morrow, GA

October 2013 to June 2016

Skills

- TIME MANAGEMENT (6 years)
- COMMUNICATION SKILLS (10+ years)
- WRITTEN AND VERBAL (10+ years)
- · Customer Service
- Mathematics
- GAAS
- GAAP
- Leadership Experience (Less than 1 year)
- Accounting (Less than 1 year)
- FD
- Clerical Experience (6 years)
- Troubleshooting
- Organizational Skills
- SAP
- Journal Entries
- General Ledger Reconciliation
- · General Ledger Accounting
- Financial Report Writing
- ERP Systems
- · Accounts Payable
- Account Reconciliation

Assessments

Customer Focus & Orientation — Highly Proficient

January 2020

Responding to customer situations with sensitivity.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share to profile/

f50e03a46416edf69f89fba177d962e9eed53dc074545cb7

Verbal Communication — Highly Proficient

August 2019

Speaking clearly, correctly, and concisely.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share_assignment/8x-oljb4pvihygy

Human Resources Skills: Recruiting — Highly Proficient

August 2019

Managing the candidate sourcing and selection process.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share assignment/6ywovajlmvznww05

Accounting: Basic Principles — Highly Proficient

April 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to prepare financial records according to federal policies.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

share_to_profile/2874f11f8250ba165010aa60793a599ceed53dc074545cb7

Human Resources Skills: Compensation and Benefits — Highly Proficient

August 2019

Knowledge of compensation and benefits programs.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share assignment/e4wywb2th0r-guf1

Teaching Skills: Elementary Classroom Management — Highly Proficient

February 2020

Managing behavior in elementary school classrooms.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share to profile/

d8bce389610d624ad05ec2b557941582eed53dc074545cb7

Professional Office Administrator (Dental) — Proficient

July 2019

Assesses personality traits that result in high-quality customer service.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share to profile/

<u>cb89c392be9827efa994da02db14148ceed53dc074545cb7</u>

Scheduling — Proficient

February 2020

Cross-referencing agendas and itineraries to avoid scheduling conflicts.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

share to profile/07df174a396d87e40ba44592fecc18b5eed53dc074545cb7

Attention to Detail — Proficient

March 2019

Identifying differences in materials, following instructions, and detecting details among distracting information.

Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/

share to profile/5ca4ebf69485d0bc27f669cbe84b643feed53dc074545cb7

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

Additional Information

A detail oriented and efficient analyst with over 13 years of experience in account analysis. As a recipient of multiple customer commendations for exceptional service, I meet and exceed key performance indicators remaining above center averages in addition to increasing peer performance by 20% in the first month of productivity.

- Microsoft Office
- Virtual Office 365
- QuickBooks Pro
- Sage Accounting Software
- Siebel Trouble Ticketing Software
- Nice Quality Evaluation Software
- Root Cause Analysis
- ERP/SAP
- Basic SQL
- CRM
- Customer service
- Conflict resolution
- Leadership
- Collaborative skills
- Analytical skills
- Time management skills
- Communication skills (written and verbal)

KEY SKILLS